Okay.
So now continuing with the logic of main_api this file
has a lot of content let me just read with you the.
The overview that I've written here, this file aims
to provide a REST API server for the front end repo.
Found out this.
Again, as literally said we have a REST API
server here using first API Python library.
And it provides some endpoints, which we can see here,
outline if we collapse this and see these functions.
All of these are endpoints.
Endpoints and what basically an endpoint mean is
that for the front frontend code, for this frontend
repo, which displays the, I'm sorry, do chat website.
If we go to the repo, which I actually have, here
locally and then search for a specific endpoint.
For example, I search for users register.
I will get its location here and if we trace back this function,
I think we can trace it back to the part of the page or the
sign up page or the sign up button and the, or register button.
And pressing that button will run this logic.
Which we'll call this endpoint.
Okay, so this endpoint is basically
this function called register user.
Okay.
With this URLI searched for this part specifically
because the API version two is part of the base RL.
So if we, if you, if we copy this and control shift if
it here in the front end repo, you won't see anything.
So that's part of the trick that you normally
sometimes substring, take substrings of the original
string that you want to search for in the repo.
So, um, Yeah so this is a file which
talks to the front end, basically.
And this is a high level of the steps that
this function has, or not steps, but what this
file does imports necessary modules obviously.
Initialize FastAPI application and configure middleware.
What does this part mean?
It means this code right here.
Okay.
We initialize an app FastAPI instance in app, and this
app object, we bind to it certain decorators, which which
like assign certain characteristics to this instance.
Okay?
So for example, exception handler here.
We say that for this application that we instantiated
right now and that we're going to run in a few seconds,
we want to make its exception handler like this.
Okay?
You, we, you can see this link for details, but
essentially what this does is if there's an error that
isn't caught below, like a try, except block if an error.
Wasn't caught in, in this blocks and
got traced it to the main code here.
Then we make sure to run this function
initially, which basically does nothing.
It literally just logs.
It just logs the issue that that happened.
But other than that, it just returns the Jason response that it
would've returned otherwise anyways this is an example, another
example of using app here is is setting up the middleware
app, middleware saying the steering, the middleware features.
Or parameters.
So one thing to note here is that we are putting
the list of origins, if you recall the origins.
We got that from the configured by which got
that from the in example file, if you remember.
Here, remember that?
So we get that list and we say that if.
The request that comes to you in the
current endpoint that has been triggered.
If that request has a host or origin in that list
of origins, then allow it, otherwise don't allow it.
And we extend actually these origins using this
function or this function does, is is take the original
origins again from the settings from the config po,
but add to them some couple of more links with URLs.
That means based on certain.
Conditions, if we're in the bug modes, and
obviously you want to add this as well, et cetera.
Okay, so what the, this is what this function does and yeah.
This is regarding the middleware.
Other logic for using the app variable.
The fast p instance is the endpoint itself, so this is an
endpoint, all of these functional endpoints, so an endpoint
basically saying app dots because we want to assign this endpoint.
Register it with this this app specifically.
Okay.
This app instance.
So if you control, click here, it'll return us back to this part.
Okay?
Okay.
Now where do we actually run this?
Like, where do we run this app?
If you control F and then, and c
the sub string of it you will see.
You will see it, it run here.
What is this?
The main condition, let me explain it.
Okay.
So basically we're saying that literally I just wrote
it in the comments programmatically start UV server
while debugging for easier control, accessibility.
So if we are.
Running the code locally.
In other words like debugging and developing, then
we can simply write Python main main do by here,
main_api.py to run it and running it this way.
Will will, will make us be able to run to run
this condition because we, this will make the name
equal mean and so we'll be able to run this block.
Actually I should have, shouldn't have wrote this.
I should have wrote it because the current directory is here.
So I have to navigate to source and then, I'm sorry.
First, so I have to write source.
And there's a tip for you if you're
using partial, you can type SR. And then.
Tab, auto complete and then tab, pressing tab again
will auto complete with the folder that you want.
So we have here on, sorry.
And sorry, backend, whatever.
That's useless folder.
We continue to on, sorry.
And then if you come back here and tab, we get a list of files.
So that's pretty helpful.
So if I write AP and it continuous.
And then if I write main, it continues
with options, and then I run this file.
So that's a very cool neat trick.
Anyways.
Yeah, so basically this is one way to run it.
This will run this which will run this script UIC, to
run the file name without extension, which is main_api.
The point is the file.
That we're currently in.
Okay.
So it'll get just this part and the colon app.
Colon app means what's the name of the instance
that you're doing and we named it app Above.
So it's app and the info that you want to run in.
And that's it.
That's it.
It'll just run it here in the server.
That's one way to do it.
Another way to do it is just to, to use that command directly.
Okay.
In in here, in the terminal.
That's another way to do that.
But I don't know.
I just prefer the Python method.
So I just wrote that if name equal main part.
Okay.
This is regarding this logic.
Here, these notes are regarding the WhatsApp logic that
I will come to that later, come back to this part later.
And I think this is the main points the custom exception handler.
I explained that database connection.
Yeah.
This is quite clear.
We just have, the database instance and an
sorry instance, which is model the agent and
the database connection to postgre SQ database.
And then we use that across the file.
If you see here, we use it multiple times to
register, to check if account exists, et cetera.
The same thing with the agent, with the Ansari agent.
We use it in multiple part.
Where do we use it?
Where do we use?
Okay.
Actually we don't use it.
Yeah, we use it in the API presenter.
Yeah.
Okay.
What does the API presenter do?
Here its logic is a little bit different
than than the other presenters.
A presenter logic is just to interface with the user
as intake input from him and then return back output.
But here presenting actually doesn't do that.
Why did we call it presenting then?
Just to remain with a, the convention.
But honestly, it should be named that for this specific case okay.
Then what does it do?
Literally nothing.
If you code the present here it's nothing we, it doesn't present.
Why does doesn it present?
Because technically, if you think about it, the
end points over here are the ones that present.
Because basically these are the things that are
the functions which interact with the front end re.
So when we get a request and it gets through one of these
functions, these are the functions which reads this request,
and these are the functions which reply back to the request.
So basically this is the interfacing layer with the user.
I mean in terms of backend at least.
So this is technically, all of this is technically the.
The present is how we are presenting to the user.
We're taking the input and presenting.
Okay, then what does the presenter do in this case?
Weirdly enough, I don't know why that choice was made,
but basically it just provides a complete function.
And what is the complete, what's the word?
Complete?
Imagine you have a chat with with
an, sorry, and you say, who are you?
And it says, I'm sorry, et cetera.
And then you.
You have now a history of messages, okay?
Between you and, I'm sorry.
And now this is called a history list of messages.
And now you send a new message and you say, okay, tell
me the pillars of a Islam, for example, and then you
want the agent to complete that chat and answer back.
So that's why we called it complete.
So what it does is take the messages and
which is which is actually a dictionary.
Which, which have two pieces of info, I believe,
if I recall correctly, the thread something related
to the thread name itself and the the messages.
What does the thread mean?
I'll come to back come to that later.
But uh, basically what we care about here
is the messages value, which is a list.
Okay?
So this value here, this here will be a list.
Even if you look at the replacement
history, you'll see that it's typing.
Here is a list of dictionaries.
Okay.
How is this structured or how is the user
message structure will come to that later?
Okay yeah, so it basically we take the history, okay,
that's currently appearing to the user in the ui.
And then we say, okay I want to, to stream the response.
Okay?
Why stream it?
Because if you remember, we want
to return the words chunk by chunk.
If you remember the yielding logic.
The generator function that we said.
Even here, if you look at this, you'll see
that it returns the generator, if you remember.
We want to return that one by one as well.
The way to do it in Python here in the code is yield.
The way to do it through the server, through
a FastAPI to the front end repo is by writing,
is by returning a streaming response object.
Streaming response is from the FastAPI library.
Okay?
This is, this automatically says to fast ai.
Okay, wait.
I'm going to return a response to the ui, but we're not done yet.
I will keep streaming the response until there's
nothing else to respond from my part as a backend code.
So this is what this part means.
And so where do we call this?
We call this in the main a p, obviously.
Okay.
In a couple of functions here the main
one of them is ad message, we call it.
And what does ad message do basically?
It runs when we make a post request to this part.
So if you see in the, an sorry website,
you will see if you open up a chat.
You will see the chat and everything, and at the top you'll
see a URL, and at the end of the UL you'll see a long hash.
That hash is the thread id.
Okay, so basically when you type a message on, sorry, and you
press enter in the front end code implicitly or behind the scenes,
we run code in the front end, which calls this endpoint with the
thrill id, similar to the ID that you see at the top of the URL.
Sorry, chat.
Okay.
And so when we call it, we pass to it.
The details that you see in the ui.
So currently in the ui, you have who are
you and, sorry, replies and whatever.
And so all of that, when you press enter to enter a new
message to submit a new message to the backend, what gets
sent is not only this message, it's this message no, sorry.
It's only this message.
Yeah.
We the previous message that UI don't get
sent again, only this message gets sent.
Okay.
And you can see it here in the Quest
because it's an ad message request object.
So if you see that object.
You'll see that just have role and control will be always
be user because the person who sends the request is a user.
So it's always called user.
Even if you call to the front end code, I think you'll see user.
Yeah, I think user.
Maybe if I put a single string.
Yeah.
Here.
Okay.
Where is it?
Return.
User core types.
User role.
Yeah, user role.
So these are possible user rules.
And so we sent the user, but I just wanna see where is this used?
Username?
Yes.
Here it is.
Okay.
So we create the the thing that we're going
to send to I'm sorry to the backend repo.
And then we, that message we specify so we specified the
rule with the user rule, which is just a user swing as
you saw, and the content, which is the message that you
just typed in the website and hit enter that message.
Okay?
That's the content.
Okay.
So that's what's written here, has to be,
this has to abide with what's written here.
Okay?
Okay.
This is something as well.
Now, after we get this last message, we, internally
in the code here, if you read the messages one by one.
You would, you'll understand what's happening.
We get the thread history, IE we get the previous messages,
which appear in neuro I, we get it from database from our side.
And so now we have the complete history of messages.
Okay.
And now we add the last message that you just sent.
When you press enter, we add that to the thread history,
and then we get all that history and then send it to the
complete presenter over here just for the LLM to compete it.
And give us the response and the response,
the streaming response will return it here.
That's it.
Obviously this is misleading because technically
this really isn't a presenter anymore.
It technically presents the complete
answer of, I'm sorry, back to the ui.
Anyways so this is initially the logic and for the main
endpoints that we have here, for the main ones, for the core.
Functionalities that we have, you'll see me adding, detailed
the comments, explaining what each part of the code does.
So I won't go into details here to be honest.
But hopefully you get just a glance and a, an
overall idea of what's happening here in this file.
I think I'm done with it.
The tricky note is recording the word
presenting, and its different meaning here.
I already explained that FanoutCache,
to be honest, is not expert in caching.
So I'm gonna explain that.
'cause I really don't know it.
I don't know how exactly it, it optimizes
our memory usage additional routers.
Yeah.
This part is actually, this part is important.
Okay.
So in summary, we have these endpoints over here and we have
endpoints related to WhatsApp in the a file called Main WhatsApp.
Okay.
You will see them here get, or whatever.
So these are endpoints as well.
Okay?
But.
In the server, we always run the script of main_api de deploy.
Okay, so now the question becomes, I want to run the endpoints
here and I want to run the endpoints in main WhatsApp Deploy.
How do I do that?
Do I run two instances, two server instances?
I, that's not really a good option.
So what we do instead is in this server that we're
running at now in this app variable that we defined
above that we defined above here, we want to somehow.
Toy or bind the endpoints of WhatsApp's endpoints.
We want to bind that with the endpoints of the
instance that we have currently running here.
Sorry for my English.
So how do we do that?
How do we do, we make this binding process by
using, include router, include the WhatsApp router.
So if we control, click here, you'll see the
router that we define in main WhatsApp by.
And so this router, which I define here, when I, whenever I
create an end point, I now add that endpoint to the router
object I created, which is here, and now I call this,
okay, in, in this file, in WhatsApp, the router object.
And now I include it here as well.
So how, where does this appear?
It appears here.
I import it from another file from the
main WhatsApp file that I just showed you.
I import outr and name it as WhatsApp router.
So that's it.
That's the whole thing.
And now the API endpoints over there will be
visible, will be in that same FSBI instance
that we have running in the live environment.
That's why if you want to test WhatsApp, you
test it by actually running the the this script,
the main_api script by running Python main_api.
So you run this to test either the main_api or the WhatsApp API.
Okay.
So this is also something for you to understand and hopefully
it's not really hard to grasp handle CORS validation.
Yeah.
Okay.
I think I might leave that part.
To another.
Yeah.
I've leave that part later.
That's the last thing remaining in this file.
The defining various API endpoints, I don't think that's
really necessary um, used to the comments that I wrote.
So yeah.
I'll start next time from the CORS validation logic.